Guide to the Manuscripts Bound in Printed Books in the Osborn Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Manuscripts Bound in Printed Books in the Osborn Collection
1719-1929
OSB MSS
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Ongoing
This list contains descriptions of and locator information for single manuscripts bound with books in the Osborn Collection.
Total Extent: ongoing
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Provenance varies with the volume.
Conditions Governing Access
The volumes are available for research.
Scope and Contents
This list contains descriptions of and locator information for single manuscripts bound with books in the Osborn Collection. The items are listed in alphabetical order by author. The shelf mark and volume number for each item is noted beside the descriptive entry.
- Documents
  - Adams, Joseph Quincy, 1881-1946 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Cornell U, Ithaca, NY, 1929 Aug 10 (Box fpe 12)
    Scope and Contents
    2 p.; 27 x 20 cm.
    Thanks for review of Tannenbaum's book
    gives description of Tannenbaum's
    temper and poor receptivity to
    criticism.
  - Alexander, Peter, 1893- ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, The University, Glasgow, 1929 Sep 18 (Box pe 213)
    1 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
    Thanks for loan of Tucker Brooke's
    paper on Henry VI.
  - Alexander, Peter Christmas card, [recipient unknown] (Box pe 291)
    1 p.; 18 x 13 cm.
    [Some textual notes concerning Richard II on reverse.]
  - Allen, Heather LS to Alvaro F. V. Ribeiro, 1980 May 6 (Box fpe 13)
    1 p.; 30 x 21 cm. [photostatic copy]
    Grants exception from 100,000-word
    limit on Oxford D.Phil. thesis
    asks for selections that the
    examiners may read to avoid reading
    the work in its entirety.
  - Ames, Joseph, 1689-1759 ALS to Morris Johnson, 1740 Jun 20 (Box fpc 27)
    2 p.; 28 x 23 cm.
    Thanks for notes on his list of English
    printers before 1600; comments on his
    current interest in cataloging
    printed works.
  - Ault, Norman, 1880-1950 ALS to Percy Simpson, Oxford, 1920 Oct 22 (Box pe 378)
    1 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
    Presents book.
  - Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913 2 ALS to John Charles Earle, Ashford, Kent, 1873 Apr 17 (Box pd 139)
    6p.; 18 x 11 cm.
    About the reception of Madonna's
    Child; no reviews; Earle to review.
  - Baldwin, Thomas Whitfield, 1890- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, London, 1931 Oct 31 (Box pe 231)
    1 p.; 15 x 21 cm.
    Reports that Prof. Hillebrand, after
    examining mss. of Percy plays, has
    determined that the stage directions
    did not show "actual acting
    conditions."
  - Bartholomew, Robert G. LS to Heathcote William Garrod, Edinburgh, 1957 Dec 18 (Box pe 49.v1)
    1 p.; 26 x 21 cm.
    Confirms existence of two places in
    Scotland, TOPER NA FUOSICH and
    DALLUNGART. (encloses hand tracing
    of DALANLUNCART from John Thompson's
    1832 Atlas of Scotland .)
  - Bartlett, Henrietta Collins, 1873-1963 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Old Lyme, CT, 1946 Sep 17 (Box pe 234)
    2 p.; 26 x 18 cm.
    Expresses pleasure that Greg will be
    able to continue bibliographic
    project.
  - Bayfield, Matthew Albert, 1852-1922 ALS to Percy Simpson, Hertingfordbury (Box pe 404)
    - Hertford, 1917 May 20
    - 4 p.; 20 x 13 cm. Seeks correction of Ben Johnson's spellings; talks about forthcoming book, A Study of Shakespeare's Versification.
  - Bayfield, Matthew Albert, 1852-1922 ALS to Percy Simpson, Hertingfordbury (Box pe 404)
    - Hertford, 1922 Mar 25
    - 2 p.; 26 x 20 cm. Offers notes; discusses orthography in Milton and Spencer; mentions cancer.
  - Bentley, Gerald Eades, 1901- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, U of Chicago, Chicago, IL, 1941 Sep 1 (Box pe 324.v1)
    Offers help with Greg's bibliographic
    work.
  - Bliss, Philip, 1787-1857 Letter in 3rd person to Henry Wellesley, St. John's College, 1819 Sep 7 (Box pc 29)
    1 p.; 11 x 10 cm.
    Returns the book and apologizes for
    delay.
  - Bone, Muirhead, 1876-1953 ALS to Percy Simpson, Oxford, 1944 Jun 25 (Box pe 385)
    2 p.; 11 x 9 cm.
    Thanks for kind letter; presents book
    by his late son, Gavin.
  - Bradley, Henry, 1845-1923 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Oxford, 1910 Aug 29 (Box pd 187)
    Discusses orthography of 15th c.
    English mss.
  - [Bradley, Henry] AL to Walter Wilson Greg, Oxford, 1910 Nov 12 (Box pd 187)
    1 p.; 9 x 14 cm.
    Refutes theory that "x" represents
    "sh" in old English mss.
  - Briggs, Grace M. ALS to P. J. Dobell, Bodleian Library, Oxford, 1946 May 13 (Box fpc 29)
    2 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
    Returning Advertisements from Parnassus (London, 1674), since the
    ms. notes cannot be authenticated
    the Bodleian therefore will not
    purchase the book.
  - Broadbent, Henry ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Eton, 1923 Feb 6 (Box pe 242)
    4 p.; 15 x 10 cm.
    Offers corrected reading of second
    folio copies in the Eton library.
  - Broadbent, Henry ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Eton, 1927 Aug 3 (Box pe 242)
    Encloses another letter for Greg's
    amusement; gives corrections in
    the order of the second folio.
  - Brooke, Charles Frederick Tucker, 1883- 1946 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Yale U, New Haven, CT, 1933 Oct 27 (Box pe 268)
    1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.
    Apologizes for late reply; cannot
    find source for attribution of Mucedorus to Collier in 1842.
  - Broome, William, 1689-1745 ALS to [unknown recipient], n.p., n.d. (Box pc 215)
    2 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
    Expresses sorrow at Fenton's death
    encloses an epitaph by Pope.
  - Brown, Sally M. LS to C. T. Campbell, British Library, London, 1978 May 12 (Box pd 235)
    1 p.; 20 x 21 cm.
    Confirms that a photostat of Edward
    Fitzgerald's signature is authentic.
  - Buchanan, Robert Williams, 1841-1901 ALS to Walter Hamilton, Boulogne-sur-Mer, France, 1882 Jul 8 (Box pd 142)
    2 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
    Responds to Hamilton's prospectus for
    a pamphlet entitled "Aesthetic
    Movement."
  - Buchanan, Robert Williams, 1841-1901 ALS to Walter Hamilton, Boulogne-sur-Mer, France, 1882 Jul 10 (Box pd 142)
    3 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
  - Bullen, Arthur Henry, 1857-1920 ALS to George Thorn-Drury, Medina Pl, London, 1901 Mar 31 (Box pe 401.v3)
    2 p.; 15 x 10 cm.
    Sends sheets (enclosures wanting)
    of Beaumont & Fletcher; goes to
    press with Walker soon; planning
    to reprint Marvell, Donne,
    Blake; new office in Charing Cross.
  - Burney, Charles, 1757-1817 ALS to William Wyndham Grenville, Baron Grenville, Greenwich, 1810 Feb 3 (Box fpd 5)
    2 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
    Offers copy of Bentley's Letters,
    edited by Burney.
  - Cadell, Thomas, 1773-1836, and William Davies, d. 1820 Letter in third person to Hannah More [Strand, London] (Box pd 248.v1)
    1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
    Amount due is £676/14/4; eight
    volumes will be ready in Feb.
  - Case, Robert Hope, 1857- ALS to Percy Simpson, Liverpool, 1932 Feb 29 (Box pe 383)
    Discusses pseudonymity; hopes to
    visit.
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Beer, Devon, 1909 Oct 5 (Box pe 44)
    2 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
    Disputes passage in Garrod's book
    on Keats.
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Beer, Devon, 1947 Apr 10 (Box pe 44)
    Asks about location of the "city"
    mentioned in preamble of the Prelude.
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Beer, Devon, 1947 Apr 13 (Box pe 44)
    Seeks information about groupings from
    1815 edition of Wordsworth's poems.
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Beer, Devon, 1947 Sep 8 (Box pe 44)
    4 p.; 18 x 13 cm.
    Concerns date of "Prospectus"; asserts
    that "the city" in the preamble is
    London.
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Beer, Devon, 1947 Sep 11 (Box pe 44)
    2 p.; 18 x 13 cm.
    Concerns dating of several Wordsworth
    poems.
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Beer, Devon, 1947 Sep 20 (Box pe 44)
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Gerrard's Cross, 1910 Jan 2 (Box pd 192.v1c2)
    Tells of a 1581 anonymous work that
    deals with theater. [There is also
    a ms. note, in Greg's hand,
    presumably to Percy Simpson.]
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Dorset, 1929 Sep 17 (Box pe 231)
    1 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
    Disagrees with Baldwin's views on
    Jones's income; notes that
    Tannenbaum will write a "scathing"
    reply to Greg's review.
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Oxford, 1938 Jan 16 (Box pd 188)
    4 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
    Proposes printing Canterbury
    Resurrection text; suggests that
    Towneley plays belong to Wakefield.
  - Chambers, Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954 ALS to [unknown recipient], Eynsham, 1933 Jul 19 (Box pe 390)
    1 p.; 14 x 9 cm.
    Corrects a student's reading of Faustus.
  - Chambers, Raymond Wilson, 1874-1942. ALS to James M. Osborn, Oxford, 1936 Jun 26 (Box pe 90)
  - Chambers, Raymond Wilson, 1874-1942 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Southgate, 1937 Apr 13 (Box pe 226)
    2 p.; 9 x 11 cm.
    Thanks for taking chair at Chambers'
    upcoming lecture.
  - Chaplin, Lord. ALS to T. Wright, Holles St., [1833] (Box pd 69)
    1 p.; 22 x 19 cm.
    Reports on health of "our poor
    invalid."
    [Ms. notes in Wright's hand on
    reverse.]
  - Chapman, Guy LS to Percy Simpson, Whitby, Yorkshire, 1929 Dec 10 (Box pe 406)
    1 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
    Will write to The Times to correct
    mistake in announcement of The Masque.
  - Chapman, Guy LS to Percy Simpson, Whitby, Yorkshire, 1930 Feb 4 (Box pe 406)
    1 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
    Thanks for help; book will be ready in
    May; trying to find music of
    Ferrabosco.
  - Clark, Arthur Melville, 1895- ALS to Percy Simpson, Edinburgh, 1931 Jun 7 (Box pe 381)
    2 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
    Comments on several plays; discusses
    sales of Thomas Heywood.
  - Clark, Elias ALS to William K. Wimsatt, Silliman Clg, Yale U, New Haven, CT, [1972] Sep 19 (Box pe 429)
    2 p.; 22 x 14 cm.
    Thanks for giving chess talk.
  - Clarke, William Kemp Lowther, 1879-1968 ALS to Evelyn Mary Simpson, Chichester Cathedral, Chichester, Sussex, 1946 Oct 17 (Box pe 398)
    2 p.; 21 x 13 cm.
    Responds on behalf of bishop of
    Chichester; explains paucity of
    Donne mss. in cathedral library.
  - Clay, Charles Travis, 1885-1978 ALS to Henrietta Tayler, House of Lords, London, 1946 Jul 2 (Box pe 361)
    Thanks for book.
  - Clayton, John R. ALS to Walter Begley, Fairfax Road, 1903 Apr 3 (Box pe 407)
    3 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
    Surprised by citation of his work
    without proper acknowledgment.
  - Cole, George Watson, 1850-1939 ALS to Percy Simpson, Pasadena, CA, 1929 Feb 16 (Box pe 394)
    2 p.; 26 x 20 cm.
    Discusses variances in copies of
    Jonson's Masque of the Gypsies
    hopes to find uncancelled copy.
  - Cole, George Watson ALS to Percy Simpson, Waldorf Hotel, Aldwych, London, 1929 Jul 22 (Box pe 394)
    Details discovery of previously unknown
    copies of Jonson's translation of
    Horace's Art of Poetry; thanks for
    hospitality.
  - Collingridge, J. R. ALS to Miss Byone, Public Records Office, [London], 1945 Sep 17 (Box pe 244)
    2 p.; 11 x 18 cm.
    Returns Greg's notes on Elizabethan
    printers' patents; includes attached
    notes on the patents taken by the
    public records office [4 p.; 33 x
    20 cm.].
  - Crofton, Margaret ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Brockenhurst, Hants., 1958 Nov 16 (Box pd 157)
    Thanks for loan of book.
  - Crow, John ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, King's College, London, 1956 May 7 (Box pe 289)
    2 p.; 8 x 14 cm.
    Provides correction to footnote in
    Greg's bibliography; criticizes
    M. W. Black.
  - Crow, John ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, King's College, London, 1956 May 23 (Box pe 261)
    2 p.; 20 x 17 cm.
    Comments on textual variants in Richard II; criticizes Matthew
    Black, Fredson Bowers, and John
    Dover Wilson
  - Cruickshank, A. H. ALS to Percy Simpson, n.p., 1921 Oct 30 (Box pd 192.v1c2)
    3 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
    Concerns questions of Shakespearian
    authorship of The Two Noble Kinsmen and other plays.
  - Dalrymple, David, Sir, 1726-1792 Observations by Lord Hailes on Lord Elibank's Letter in the Remarks, n.d. (Box pc 290)
    11 p.
    MS copy of notes "found in MS."
    after the death of Lord Hailes,
    added to blanks at the end of A Letter to the Honorable David Dalrymple, Lord Hailes... (Edinburgh: Balfour & Smellie, 1773).
    Acc.: 02.1.8
  - Davin, Daniel LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Oxford, 1953 Jan 27 (Box pe 230)
    1 p.; 13 x 20 cm.
    Comments on difficulty of reading
    Kenneth Sisam's book, Studies in the History of Old English Lit..
  - Davin, Daniel ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Oxford, 1958 Aug 25 (Box pe 283)
    1 p.; 17 x 20 cm.
    Promises copy of forthcoming Clarendon
    Press book.
  - Davin, Daniel LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Oxford, 1959 Jan 22 (Box pe 228)
    Concerns editions of An Introduction to Bibliography, by McKerrow.
  - Davies, Randall, 1866-1946 ALS to George Thorn-Drury, Westminster, 1907 Dec 9 (Box pe 407)
    1 p.; 21 x 13 cm.
    An attempt at putting Hall's and
    Marsden's evidence into shape.
  - Davis, Emily ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Oxford, 1957 Feb 15 (Box pe 362)
    Presents book, by Joyce Cary, printed
    by her spouse, Herbert Davis.
  - Davis, Herbert John, 1893-1967 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, New Bodleian, Oxford, 1958 Nov (Box pe 329)
  - Davis, Herbert John, 1893-1967 ALS to James M. Osborn, Iffley, Oxford (Box pe 131)
    1 p.; 11 x 18 cm.
    Presents Twelve Poems of John
    Buxton.
  - Davis, Herbert John, 1893-1967 ALS to Percy Simpson, New Bodleian, Oxford, 1952 Jul 26 (Box pe 414)
    1 p.; 12 cm.
    Sending a book.
  - Davis, Herbert John, 1893-1967 ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Toronto, Canada, 1957 Feb 12 (Box pe 362)
    2 p.; 25 x 19 cm.
    Will ask spouse [Emily] to send Cary
    book.
  - Dawson, Giles Edwin, 1903- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Folger Shakespeare Library, Washington, DC, 1946 Jul 31 (Box pe 265)
    1 p.; 25 x 21 cm.
    Sends offprint and solicits reaction.
  - Dawson, Giles Edwin, 1903- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Folger Shakespeare Library, Washington, DC, 1956 Aug 27 (Box pe 312)
    1 p.; 18 x 14
    Describes Folger copy of The Troublesome Reign of King John; will
    send photostatic copy.
  - Day, Mabel ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, London, 1940 Aug 20 (Box pe 224)
    2 p.; 13 x 21 cm.
    Asks Greg to remain in Early English
    Text Society (on the committee)
    mentions upcoming committee meeting.
  - Dent, Edward Joseph, 1876-1957 ALS to Mantague Summers, Cambridge, 1933 Mar 8 (Box pe 186)
    Identifies a round by John Jenkins
    apologizes for notice of an error by
    Summers.
  - Dobell, Bertram, 1842-1914 ALS to Percy Simpson, [London], 1906 Jan 17 (Box pe 400)
    Thanks for help; has ms. book of
    dramatic speeches to lend.
  - Dobell, Bertram, 1842-1914 ALS to Percy Simpson, [London], 1908 Apr (Box pd 192.v1c2)
    Offers to lend a ms. copy of "The
    City Madame," or variant of it
    mentions 1585 book in his possession
    with "W. Sha" signature.
  - Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937 LS to C. H. Wilkinson, London, 1928 Jan 31 (Box pe 360)
    Invites Wilkinson to dinner and
    lecture.
  - Duthie, George Ian LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Montreal, Canada, 1953 Sep 20 (Box pe 216)
    3 p.; 18 x 14 cm.
    Discusses problems in editing
    Shakespeare; mentions Alice Walker's
    new book.
  - Egan, L. J. S. LS to John Betjeman, Shepherds Bush, London, 1957 Aug 21 (Box pe 59)
    1 p.; 21 x 18 cm.
    Solicits work preserving architectural
    decorations in older homes.
  - Ellis, Arthur ALS to Henrietta Tayler, British Museum, London, 1946 June 25 (Box pe 361)
  - Ellis, Henry, 1777-1869 ALS to John Caley, 1809 Oct 31 (Box pc 53)
    1 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
    Suggests that an index rerun of the
    Domesday book would be useful; he
    is willing to undertake the task.
    Ms. copy, in Ellis's hand.
  - Eleanore [last name unknown] ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, [Greece], 1957 Sep 6 (Box pe 295)
    1 p.; 8 x 13 cm.
    Greetings from cruise ship.
  - Evans, Arthur William ALS to Leonard Wibley, London, 1932 May 12 (Box pe 157)
  - [Feilding, Robert, 1650 or 15-1712]: 3 DS relating to his trial for bigamy (Box fpc 57)
    accompanying a copy of "The Arraignment,
    Tryal, and Conviction of Robert
    Feilding, Esq., for Felony...."
    (London: 1708)
    1) "The Information of Charlotte Henrietta
    Villers....:" DS, 1706 Sep 9
    2) "The Information of Michael Rosse....:"
    DS, 1706 Sep 9
    3) royal warrant postponing the sentencing
    of Feilding, DS signed by Queen Anne and
    countersigned by Robert Harley, Earl of
    Oxford, 1706 Dec 4.
  - Fellowes, Edmund H., 1870-1951 ALS to Percy Simpson, Windsor Castle, 1926 May 12 (Box pe 382)
    Discusses numerous errors in first
    edition of English Madrigal Verse
    solicits opinion on several textual
    points.
  - Fellowes, Edmund H., 1870-1951 ALS to Percy Simpson, Windsor Castle, 1926 May 22 (Box pe 382)
    Thanks for help; lists textual problems
    in preparing second edition.
  - Fellowes, Edmund H., 1870-1951 ALS to Percy Simpson, Windsor Castle, 1926 May 25 (Box pe 382)
    3 p.; 15 x 10 cm.
    Asks opinion on a problem of aligning
    text and music.
  - Fellowes, Edmund H., 1870-1951 ALS to Percy Simpson, Windsor Castle, 1926 Jul 29 (Box pe 382)
    3 p.; 15 x 11 cm.
    Adds corrections; wonders about sales
    and costs of second edition.
  - Fellowes, Edmund H., 1870-1951 ALS to Percy Simpson, Windsor Castle, 1927 May 13 (Box pe 382)
    1 p.; 11 x 9 cm.
    Confirms reading.
  - Fellowes, Edmund H., 1870-1951 ALS to Percy Simpson, Windsor Castle, 1947 Jul 17 (Box pe 382)
    1 p.; 18 x 14 cm.
    Seeks advice on textual question in a
    madrigal.
  - Feuillerat, Albert, 1874-1953 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Bayswater, London, 1905 Sep 21 (Box pe 328)
    Invites Greg to tea.
  - Feuillerat, Albert, 1874-1953 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Bayswater, London, 1905 Sep 23 (Box pe 328)
    Confirms meeting time.
  - Feuillerat, Albert, 1874-1953 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Rennes, France, 1905 Nov 15 (Box pe 328)
    Encloses book.
  - Fisher, Herbert Albert Laurens, 1865-1940 ALS to Sir Ernest Benn, New Clg, Oxford, 1928 Nov 9 (Box pe 430)
    Hopes to begin "something in a big
    scale."
  - Fletcher, Charles Robert Leslie, 1857- 1934 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Oxford, 1925 Aug 15 (Box pd 34)
    Thanks for help.
  - Foster, William LS to Percy Simpson, [London], 1941 Jun 19 (Box pd 192.v1c2)
    4 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
    Asks about origin of dysphemism for
    Dutch people, "Hans Beerpot"
    comments on wartime conditions,
    particularly in London.
  - Francis, Frank Chalton, 1901- ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, British Museum, London (Box pe 211)
    1 p.; 9 x 17 cm.
    Confirms that a collection of
    facsimiles was done under the
    auspices of Richard Garnett in 1897.
  - Fry, Mary Isabel LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, San Marino, CA, 1956 Aug 28 (Box pe 312)
    States that formal permission to
    reproduce The Taming of the Shrew and King John will be forthcoming.
  - Fry, Mary Isabel LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, San Marino, CA, 1957 Apr 29 (Box pe 283)
    Provides reading of Kemble-Devonshire Richard III.
  - Gardner, Helen ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, St. Hilda's Clg, Oxford, 1950 Jan 14 (Box pe 46.v1)
    2 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
    On Donne's description of himself as
    armiger, as well as the Donne family
    crest and letter seals.
  - Gardner, Helen ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, St. Hilda's Clg, Oxford, 1950 Jun 9 (Box pe 46.v1)
    3 p.; 12 x 20 cm.
    Concerns source of the motto under the
    portrait prefixed to Donne's Death's Duell.
  - Gardner, Helen ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, St. Hilda's Clg, Oxford, 1950 Jun 11 (Box pe 46.v1)
    Points out that "syndon" [sic] was an
    English word in Donne's time; has to
    finish her work by August.
  - Gardner, Helen ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, St. Hilda's Clg, Oxford, 1954 Nov 20 (Box pe 46.v1)
    Discusses poems about fleas; suggests
    some sources.
  - Garnett, Richard, 1835-1906 ALS to Walter Begley, Hampstead, 1903 Apr 27 (Box pe 407)
    Thanks for copy of Is it Shakespeare?, hopes to have Twilight of the Gods for Begley
    soon; a little on Bacon-Shakespeare
    question.
  - Gibson, Strickland, 1877-1958 2 ALS to Sir Walter Greg, 1936 Jun 20, 23 (Box pe 336)
    2 p.
    Concerning Higden's Polychronicon.
  - Gibson, Strickland, 1877-1958 ALS to Percy Simpson, Oxford, 1955 Apr 12 (Box pe 399)
    2 p.; 18 x 14 cm.
    Comments on Studies in Elizabethan Drama; presents book.
  - Giles, A.H. ALS to Augustus Jessopp, London, 1909 May 2 (Box pd 156)
    Searching for Dürer print of
    St. Giles.
  - Gray, John Miller, 1850-1894 ALS to Walter Hamilton, Edinburgh, 1882 Jul 8 (Box pd 142)
    Subscribes to forthcoming volume
    mentions Buchanan's letter in Academy recanting attacks on
    Fleshly school.
  - Gray, Pamela ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Alwick, Northumberland, n.y. Sep 28 (Box pe 44)
    Compliments on book; invites to lunch.
  - Grenville, Thomas, 1755-1846 ALS to Samuel Rogers, n.p., n.d. (Box pd 124)
    1 p.; 14 x 7 cm.
    Discusses parts of Rogers' book.
  - Grey, R. P. ALS to Walter Begley, Buntingford, Hertfordshire (Box pe 407)
    5 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
    14 items contending Baconian thesis.
  - Greg, Walter Wilson, 1875-1959 ALS to Percy Simpson, Wimbledon, 1917 Jan 22 (Box pd 192.v1c2)
    Tells of article in a 1911 issue of Library.
  - C. B. H. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Trinity Clg, Cambridge, 1923 Feb 5 (Box pe 242)
    1 p.; 9 x 11 cm.
    folio of Shakespeare.
  - Hadfield, John ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Hitchin, Herts., 1951 Mar 20 (Box pe 358)
    Finalizes details of book loan
    requests additional books.
  - Hamilton, Walter, 1844-1899 ALS to Robert Buchanan, London, 1882 Jul 10 (Box pd 142)
    On Hamilton's pamphlet, which mentions
    Buchanan's attack, about Aesthetic
    School of poetry.
  - Hanson, L. W. LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Bodleian Library, Oxford, 1956 Jul 19 (Box pe 309)
    Reports that the Bodley bought Malone
    870, The First Part of the Contention of York and Lancaster in the Heber sale of 1834.
  - Harper, George McLean, 1863-1947 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Princeton, NJ, 1923 Oct 10 (Box pe 43.v1)
    6 p.; 18 x 15 cm.
    Thanks for copy of "Wordsworth," as
    well as frequent citations within it
    comments on Garrod's treatment of
    Wordsworth.
  - Harris, D. Beatrice LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Petworth, 1956 Jul 28 (Box pe 289)
    2 p.; 15 x 19 cm.
    Invites Greg to come examine a copy
    of Richard II.
  - Harrison, George Bagshawe, 1894- ALS to Percy Simpson, Stortford., 1934 Apr 3 (Box pe 387)
  - Hart, H. C. ALS to Walter Begley, Carrablagh, Portsalon, Co. Donegal, n.y. May 8 (Box pe 407)
    Looks forward to reading Is it Shakespeare?; identifies Labeo
    differently.
  - Haward, Lawrence, 1878- ALS to Percy A. Scholes, City Art Gallery, Manchester, 1942 Feb 17 (Box fpe 3)
    1 p.; 26 x 20 cm.
    Asks if Scholes knows about a portrait
    of Charles Burney by Nathaniel Dance.
  - Haward, Lawrence, 1878- ALS to Percy A. Scholes, City Art Gallery, Manchester, 1942 Mar 4 (Box fpe 3)
    Concerns authenticity of a portrait of
    Charles Burney.
  - Haward, Lawrence, 1878- ALS to Percy A. Scholes, City Art Gallery, Manchester, 1942 Mar 18 (Box fpe 3)
  - Haward, Lawrence, 1878- ALS to Percy A. Scholes, City Art Gallery, Manchester, 1943 Sep 3 (Box fpe 3)
    On portraits of the Burneys.
  - Haward, Lawrence, 1878- ALS to Percy A. Scholes, City Art Gallery, Manchester, 1943 Sep 17 (Box fpe 3)
    Returns photographs.